Guide to the Records of the North American Jewish Students Appeal, undated, 1962, 1964-1996 (bulk 1971-1995) *I-338 and *I-338A
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
- Series VIII: Ephemera and Posters, undated, 1971-1995; Box 110-111.
  - Subseries 2: Posters, undated, 1973-1995; Box 111 (Folders 4-8).
    - Beneficiary Grants
      - Hillel Calendar of Events at University of Michigan, 1987, 1993 (Box 111, Folder 7)
      - Israel Week Newspaper Advertising, University of Florida Oracle and Unknown Publication, undated, May 1980 (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - Others
      - Coalition for Alternatives in Jewish Education (CAJE) Conference on Alternatives in Jewish Education, 1985 (Box 111, Folder 7)
      - "Generating Change: Understanding Jewish Ideas and Activating the Civic Agenda" Spitzer Forum on Public Policy Poster, 1994 (Box 111, Folder 7)
      - Jerusalem Fellowship (Senators Moynihan and Specter) Poster and Flyer, 1994 (Box 111, Folder 7)
      - New Voices Newspaper Advertising, Ad-Hoc Committee for a National Union of Jewish Students, 1991 (Box 111, Folder 7)
      - World Union of Jewish Students (WUJS) Arad, Israel Graduate Center Poster, [1979] (Box 111, Folder 7)
      - "Visions and Voices" Interfaith Marriage Symposium Visual Aids and Questionnaire (see also Box 27, Folder 5), undated, [1993] (Box 111, Folder 8)
      - The New Torch(New York University), Various Issues [Separated for size](See box 107e for other issues), 1979 (Box 111, Folder 9)
      - Appeal Buttons, various, undated (Box 111, Folder 10)
- Series IX: Photographs, undated, 1972-1995; Box 112.
  Arranged in no particular order.
  Series X contains three videotapes and one audiotape. The audiotape derives from approximately the late 1970s to early 1980s, sometime during the leadership of Susan Dessel. The tape has instructions from Trustee Steven Cohen on how Trustees or Governing Board members should present allocation requests to the Federations. Toward the end of the tape, Ms. Dessel offers her own thoughts on specific approaches.
  Two of the videotapes are presentation videotapes created by the APPEAL in the 1990s for promotional purposes. The final videotape is of a University of Michigan lecture given by Dr. Leon Bass in 1994. Dr. Bass was an African-America soldier who was one of the first to view the Buchenwald concentration camp. The videotape captures his recollections of this experience.
  - Glazer, Ron Photography Exhibit Negative, circa 1975-1976 (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - NAJSA Event; Possibly Award Being Given to Brenda Gevertz or the Appeal Negatives, circa 1990s
  - Golda Meir Stock Photograph, BxW, 8x10, undated (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - B'Nai B'Rith Lecture Bureau, Elie Wiesel and David Grossman Photographs, BxW, 5x7, undated, 1988 (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - Stone, Howard, Director, UJA Young Leadership Cabinet, BxW, 8x10, circa 1972 (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - SSSJ "Run for Freedom" Event at Columbia University Library, BxW, 5x7, [September 17, 1982] (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - SSSJ Meeting Photographic Proofs (2), April 24, 1985 (Box 112)
  - YUGNTRUF Summer Retreat Snapshot, undated (Box 112, Folder 6)
  - YUGNTRUF Publicity Shot, BxW, 8x10, 1977
  - NETWORK Caravan Lecture by Zvi Beckerman Snapshot, circa December 1983
  - NAJSA Brochure Mock-Up Photograph with 10 Students and 3 Candles, 3x2, BxW, January 1974 (Box 112, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Renaissance Conference, University of California - Berkeley, 1995 (Box 112, Folder 8)
  - NY Board of Rabbis, Israel Opportunities and Aliyah Conference, 3 Snaps, BxW, 1985 (Box 112, Folder 9)
  - Award Ceremony, 20 snapshots, BxW, undated (Box 112, Folder 10)
  - Unknown Event, Possibly PZC, 3 Women with "For Israel's Sake, Really Seek Peace" Banner, 4 Color Snapshots (2 each), undated (Box 112, Folder 11)
  - NAJSA Pool Party at Brenda Gevertz' House, 8 4x5 and 21 5x7 Color Snapshots, [1994?] (Box 112, Folder 12)
  - Levinson-Friedman Engagement Proposal Photographs, 2 Color Snapshots, 1988 (Box 112, Folder 13)
  - SSSJ, [Avital Schransky], N.Y. "Let My People Go" Rally, [1984] (Box 112, Folder 14)
  - Leuchter, Magda Shenberg, NAJSA Chairperson Photographs, 3 4x6 Bxw, 1 2.5x3.5 BxW, undated (Box 112, Folder 15)
  - General Assembly Photographs, 32 3x5 Snapshots, 1987 (Box 112, Folder 16)
  - Israel Awareness Week, "Israel Bazaar," Indiana University, 4 3x5 Color Photographs with Captions, [1979] (Box 112, Folder 17)
  - "Shletl Wedding," 1st Annual Yiddishkeit Festival, Columbia University, 10 5x7 Color Photographs with, 1995 (Box 112, Folder 18)
  - Yom HaShoah Name Reading, Northwestern University, 5 4x6 Color Photographs, 1994 (Box 112, Folder 19)
  - University of Minnesota Students, U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum, 1 4x6 Color, [1994] (Box 112, Folder 20)
  - "Back to the Future: Shaping Judaism for the 21st Century" M.I.T. Banner, 1 4x6 color, [1993]
  - Middlebury College and Williams College "Weekend at Williams," 2 4x6 Color Photographs, Jan. 1993 (Box 112, Folder 21)
  - Community Model Seder, William Patterson College, 2 3x5 Color Photographs, April. 1992 (Box 112, Folder 22)
  - Yom Ha'Atzmaut Day, W. of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, 5 3x5 Color Photographs, [1991] (Box 112, Folder 23)
  - Russian Olim Housing Studio Project, University of Texas, 3 3x5 Color Photographs, [1991] (Box 112, Folder 24)
  - Florida State International Jewish Awareness Celebration Banner, 1 3x5 Color, [1986-1987] (Box 112, Folder 25)
  - San Diego University Tagar Zionist Activist Movement Programming Photos, 1 3x5 BxW, 1 3x5 Color, 1990
  - McGill University, PZC Seminar Photographs, 2 4x6 Color, 1991 (Box 112, Folder 26)
  - University of Carolina Southeast Regional Conference Spring Retreat, 1 4x6 Color, 1991
  - Fetterman, Larry Family Photograph, circa 1973 (Box 112, Folder 27)
  - Constituent Activities [YUGNTRUF?] Negatives, 3 2x3 Negs, undated (Box 112, Folder 28)
  - NAJSA Lecture, Unknown Location, Unknown Event, 13 4x6 Color Photographs, undated (Box 112, Folder 29)
- Series X: Video and Audio Tapes, undated, 1990s; Box 110.
  - Federation Presentation Hints Audio Tape, undated (Box 110, Folder 1A)
  - "Jewish Students Have APPEAL!" NAJSA Presentation Video, circa 1990s (Box 110, Folder 2A)
  - "Jewish Students Have APPEAL!" NAJSA Presentation Video, circa 1990s (Box 110, Folder 3A)
  - University of Michigan Holocaust Remembrance, Dr. Leon Bass Lecture Video, 1994 (Box 110, Folder 4A)
- Collection Addendum I-338A: North American Jewish Students' Appeal, undated, 1967-1996; 4.13 linear ft. (4 .5 boxes; 1 .25 box; 1 11 x 17 box; 1 16 x 20.)
  This Collection Addendum, added to the overall collection in 2004, follows the series structure of the entire collection as closely as possible. Some series are represented while others are not, depending on the type of material within the addendum.
  The provenance of this Collection Addendum is as follows: Brenda Gervertz, Executive Director of the organization from 1989-1995, donated the Records of the North American Jewish Students Appeal to the American Jewish Historical Society. Gervertz donated this additional collection, mostly detailing the latter years of the organization, in 2004.
  While the materials are unique, they are not much different from the overall collection except in the materials specifically outlining the demise of the North American Jewish Students Appeal, primarily located in Box 1.
  - Series I: Board of Trustees, Governing Board, Friends and Rabbis, undated, 1971-1995
    - Subseries 1: Board of Trustees, undated, 1993
      - Correspondence, Notes, and Planning Documents, undated, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Subseries 2: Governing Board, 1991-1995
      - By-Laws/Suspension of the NAJSA, circa 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, Memos, Articles and Notes, undated, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Federation Request Letters, Memorandums, Data Reports, Allocations, Minutes, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Final Report Correspondence, Notes, and Drafts, undated, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Final Report and Notes, undated, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Gevertz, Brenda APPEAL Statement, May 17, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Minutes, Grant Proposals, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Minutes, Grant Proposals, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Minutes, Misc. Documents, undated 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Series II: Organizational Records, undated, 1971-1996
    - Subseries 1: General Records, undated, 1967-1995
      - Activists Program Records, undated, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Anti-Semitism and Anti-Zionism Articles, Reports, and Memoranda, undated, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Anti-Semitism on Campus Reports, Speeches and Articles, undated, 1979-1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Anti-Semitism on Campus Reports, Speeches and Articles, undated, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Association of Jewish Community Organization (AJCOP) Personnel History Pamphlet (AJCOP, 1969-1987), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Association of Jewish Community Organization (AJCOP) Personnel - Women's Issues Committee Correspondence, Articles, Reports, and Documents, 1985- 1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Change and the Jewish Professional Conference, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Committee on Professional Staff Development (AJCOP) Memos, Notes and Reports, undated, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Conference on Alternatives in Jewish Education (CAJE) Fundraising Seminar Notes, circa 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Horstein Advisory Committee, Brandeis University Correspondence, Minutes, and Documents, undated, 1990-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Jewish Students/CJH-Hillel "Alignment" Issues Ad-hoc Committee Minutes, January 27, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Jewish University Student Services Task Force Correspondence, Notes and Planning Documents, undated, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jewish Women Articles, Bibliographies and Notes, undated, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Jewish Youth Movement Reports and Articles, undated, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Mailing Lists (Trustees, Governing Board and other), undated, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - "New Visions for Serving Jewish University Students," Council of Jewish Federations Draft and Final Report, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Northern Ohio Union of Jewish Students "Jewish Resistance" Program, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Personnel Manuals, Articles, and Policies, undated, 1985-1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Press Releases, Program, Statements, Misc., undated, 1967, 1974-1975, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Social Action Programming Correspondence, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Spitzer Forum on Public Policy (B'nai B'rith/Hillel Foundations) Program and Roster, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Series II: Organizational Records, undated, 1971-1996
    - Series II: Financial Records, undated, 1974-1996; (Bulk 1993-1994)
      - Bills, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Federation Donations and Expenditures, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Gevertz, Brenda Work File (Restricted), undated, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Levine, Ellen Work File (Restricted), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Petty Cash Record Book, 1974-1993 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - State Insurance Fund Payments and Correspondence, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Work Files, Various (Restricted), 1988, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Series IV: Beneficiary Grants, undated, 1971-1995
    - Subseries 1: General Records, circa 1995
      - NAJSA Program Report (1986-1995), circa 1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Subseries 2: Grants Made By Program Year, undated
      - New Ohio Union of Jewish Students (NOUJS) Education Packet, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Series VI: Fundraising, undated, 1972-[1996]
    - Grantsmanship Background Materials, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "How to Write a Successful Grant Proposal" Federation of Jewish Philanthropy of New York Seminar Material, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Funders Network Annual Conference Registration Packet, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Funders Network Meeting, Speakers Remarks, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Jewish Funders Network Third Annual National Conference (“Continuity and Transition: What and How to Fund”) Selected Readings, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Series VII: Publications and Printed Matter, undated, 1969, 1971-1995
    - Subseries 1: Constituents, 1973, 1975
      - NETWORK: A Guide to Jewish Student Groups vol. II, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Yungtruf: Yugntruf: A Yiddish Student Quarterly, September 1974, January 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Series VIII: Publications and Printed Material, undated, 1971-1995
    - Subseries 3: Others: Journals, Newsletters, Newspapers and Printed Matter, 1968-1994
      - Ari, December 1973 and 1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Bagolah, Ichud Habonim Labor Zionist Youth, December 1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - “Clearing House: A Professional Bulleting for Hillel Directors and Counselors”, November 1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Congress Bi-Weekly: A Journal of Opinion and Jewish Affairs, October 28, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Davka, Fall and Winter 1974, Spring 1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Elul: Holocaust and Resistance, February 1972 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Flashpoint: Magazine of the Israel Palestine Socialist Action Group[U.K.], Summer 1973 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Fundraising Organizations Newsletters, undated, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Hakotz (The Thorn), Syracuse University, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - "HERitage and HIStory: Visions for an Equal Future," A Sourcebook on Jewish Women's Issues, WUJS, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Hillel Programs, undated, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - "Is Hillel for Nerds?"Moment, February 1995/Adar 5755 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Jewits, Spring no year (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Jewish Boston: A Guide to Jewish Life in the Greater Boston Jewish Community, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Jewish Funders Network Jewish World"The Money Crunch" Articles, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Jewish Women Publications, 1971-1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - "Jewish Women: A Hillel Program Guide for the Campus Community", 1994 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Lilith, Fall 1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Lillit, October 13, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - "Musar Anthology: A Moral and Aesthetic Challenge to a War-Weary World," First Edition, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - New Dor: A Jewish Student Magazine, September 1973 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Radical Judaism Articles, undated, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Raising Jewish Consciousness Articles, undated, 1973, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Youth and Nation: Magazine for Radical Jewish Youth published by Hashomir Hatzair, September-October 1974 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Series IX: Photographs, undated
    - Gevertz, Brenda, with unidentified students and APPEAL t-shirt, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Oversized Materials; Series VII: Publications and Printed Matter, undated, 1969, 1971-1995
    - Subseries 1: Constituents, undated, 1974-1975, 1992-1995
      - Jewish Student Press Service: New Voices, May/June 1992, March 1993, November 1994, February 1995 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Network: Network, undated, January 18, 1974, March 1975, June 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Subseries 3: Other, 1971-1999, undated, 1969, 1971-1995
      - Genesis 2: Newspaper of Boston's Jewish Student and Young Adult Community, January 1975, February 25, 1975, March 1975 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Hashofar: Publication of the Northern Ohio Union of Jewish Students, March 1971, April 1971, October 1971, January 1972, Passover, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Jewish Funders Network Jewish World, "The Money Crunch" Articles, and Jewish Women Articles, 1972, 1974, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Newspapers, Various, B-H, 1972-1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Newspapers, Various, J-S, 1974-1999 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Source, The, December 19, 1973, February 26, 1975, March 13, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Series VIII: Ephemera, undated
    - Corporate Seal Impression (original seal discarded), undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "Do the Write Thing: A National Symposium on Jewish Issues for Campus Media", undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "Jewish Students Have Appeal!" Balloon Kite Kit, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "Jewish Students Have Appeal!" Balloon Kite Sealed Packages (3), undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - "Jewish Students Have Appeal" Pens (one in Pink and one in Yellow, 2 pens), undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "Jewish Students Have Appeal!" T-shirt, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - NAJSA "I'm a Friend of the Students" White with Red, Blue and Black Texts Button, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - NAJSA "I'm Good Enough, I'm Smart Enough, and Doggonit, Students Like Me!" Button on White Background, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - NAJSA in Small Caps with Small Star of David Button, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - NAJSA with Star of David and "A" in Middle Button (3 buttons), undated (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
    - "Support Student Leadership" Jewish Students Appeal, Red and White Button (3 buttons), undated (Box 7, Folder 13-15)
  - Series X: Video and Audio Tapes, undated, 1990s
    - Promotion and Merchandising Videos, undated, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 14-16)